Welcome back, In this video we're going to wrap up our presentations on lexical
欢迎回来，在这段视频中，我们将结束我们关于词汇的演讲。
analysis with the discussion of how we implement Finite Automata, using a variety
分析和讨论我们如何实现有限自动机，使用各种
of different techniques. Just to review, here's our little flow chart of how
不同的技术。回顾一下，这是我们的小流程图
lexical analyzers are constructed. And today we're going to be focusing on this
构建了词法分析器。今天我们要关注的就是这一点
last step. The implementation of DFA's and actually I should say that this chart is
最后一步。DFA的实现，实际上我应该说这个图表是
not quite completely accurate because sometimes we don't go all the way to
不完全准确，因为有时我们不会一直走到
DFA's. We stop with NFA's and we implement them directly and so we'll talk a little
DFA。我们不再讨论NFA，而是直接实现它们，所以我们会稍微谈一谈
bit about that. What if we didn't want to build a DFA and instead wanted to base our
关于这一点。如果我们不想构建DFA，而是想基于我们的
lexical analyzers directly on an NFA. So, beginning now with DFA's, It's very simple
直接在NFA上使用词法分析器。所以，现在从DFA开始，非常简单
to implement a deterministic finite automaton as an array. There's dimensional
将确定性有限自动机实现为数组。有次元的
array and one of the dimensions will be the state. So we might have states here
数组，其中一个维度将是状态。所以我们这里可能有州
and the other dimension will be the input symbols. And so I might have a state i and
另一个维度将是输入符号。所以我可能有一个状态，我和
then input A and I simply look up in that position and there will be the next state
然后输入A，我只需在该位置上查找，就会有下一个状态
k to which we're going to move. So the table stores at every particular input
我们要移到K。因此，该表在每个特定的输入上都进行存储
symbol and state, the next state that the machine will move to. So, let's do an
符号和状态，机器将移动到的下一个状态。那么，让我们来做一个
example of converting a deterministic automaton into a table driven
将确定性自动机转换为表驱动的示例
implementation so here is the automaton that we built last time and recall that
实现，这是我们上次构建的自动机，回想一下
several videos ago. We started with a regular expression which we convert into a
几个视频之前。我们从正则表达式开始，将其转换为
non-deterministic finite automaton and then we converted it to a deterministic
非确定性有限自动机，然后我们把它转换成确定性的
automaton just in the last video. And here it is again and now let's talk about how
机器人就在最后一段视频里。现在又来了，现在让我们来谈谈如何
to realize it as a table. So draw 2-dimensional table and there are three
把它变成一张桌子。所以画一个二维表有三个
states so we will need three rows. And just label these rows S, T, and U and then
所以我们需要三排。只需将这些行标记为S、T和U，然后
there are two inputs, zero and one and now let's fill in the entries in the table.
有两个输入，0和1，现在让我们填充表中的条目。
So, in state S on input zero, where do we go? We go to state T. So, the entry in the
那么，在输入0的状态S中，我们该去哪里呢？我们去T州。所以，条目中的
S0 entry will be T. And some really from state S input one will wind up in state U.
S0条目将是T，而一些真正来自状态S的输入1将最终到达状态U。
So on so the S1 entry will be U, okay? And then certainly for the other the other
所以S1条目将是U，好吗？当然，对另一个人来说，对另一个人来说
rows of the table let's do the T row next on one we go to U and on zero we stay in
表中的各行，让我们做T行，下一行在1上，我们转到U，在0上，我们留在原地
T. So, this, this row is also TU. And finally for U, what happens well, on zero
T那么这，这一排也是TU。最后，对于你来说，什么是好的，在零的情况下
we go to T and on one we stay in U so this row is also TU and there's our table. That
我们去T，在一，我们留在U，所以这一排也是TU，这是我们的桌子。那
describes the transition relation of the automaton. And now if we would think about
描述了自动机的转移关系。现在如果我们想一想
how we would use this transition relation in a program, you can easily imagine. We
我们将如何在程序中使用这种过渡关系，您可以很容易地想象到。我们
would start out say with our input index. Porting to the beginning of the input and
会从我们的输入索引开始。移植到输入的开头，然后
let's call that zero and we can have to have a current state and we start at the
让我们称它为零，我们必须有一个当前状态，我们从
start state, let's just say that that's row zero so in this case that would be row
开始状态，假设这是第0行，所以在本例中这将是第0行
S. And then while what we wanted to do, we wanted to walk over the input. And check
然后，当我们想要做的时候，我们想要遍历输入。并勾选
whether, and checking on it, you know and make the transitions for each element of
您是否了解并检查，并对每个元素进行转换
the input one at a time and we want to stop when the input is empty. So while
输入一次一个，我们希望在输入为空时停止。所以虽然
there is still as input, let's say we have an array of characters that is our, that
仍然有作为输入的，假设我们有一个字符数组，它是我们的，也就是
is our input and while the entry in that array is not null, let's do the following.
是我们的输入，当该数组中的条目不为空时，让我们执行以下操作。
We're gonna update the state. At each step and what are we gonna update it to let's
我们会更新州政府的最新情况。在每一步，我们要对其进行哪些更新，让我们
give this array a name. Let's call this array A. So, we're gonna look up in our
为此数组指定一个名称。我们称这个数组为A。所以，我们将在我们的
transition relation A and what are we going to use? Well, we're gonna look up
过渡关系A，我们要用什么呢？好的，我们要往上看
the current state, And we're going to look up the input. And in that entry I think,
当前状态，我们将查找输入。我认为在那个词条里，
you know? Using the, the current state and the current input, we're gonna transition
你知道?使用、当前状态和当前输入，我们将转换
to a new state and we also wanted to increment the input pointer. So we'll do
设置为新状态，并且我们还希望递增输入指针。所以我们就这么做
that at the same time. And there is our loop that processes an input according to
在同一时间。还有我们的循环，它根据
the transition table A. And as you can see this is a very compact, very efficient
转换表A，如您所见，这是一个非常紧凑、非常高效的
process. Just really, just a little bit of index arithmetic and one two table look
进程。真的，只需要一点索引算法和一个两个表的查找
ups, one for the input and one for the state transition table per character of
UPS，一个用于输入，另一个用于每个字符的状态转换表
input. So that's really hard to imagine having a process that's much faster or
输入。所以这真的很难想象会有一个更快的过程，或者
more compact than this. Now that was one strategy for implementing a deterministic
比这个更紧凑。这是实现确定性的一种策略
finite automaton and you may have noticed that one disadvantage of that particular
有限自动机，你可能已经注意到它的一个缺点
approach was that there were a lot of duplicate rows in the table. In fact all
方法是表中有很多重复的行。事实上，所有的
the rows of the table were exactly the same and we could save some space by using
表中的行完全相同，我们可以使用以下命令节省一些空间
a slightly different representation. So instead of having a 2-dimensional table,
略有不同的表现。所以不是有一个二维表，
we can just have a 1-dimensional table and this table again. Would be one entry for
我们可以只有一个一维表，然后再有这个表。将是一个条目，用于
each state so S, T, and U. And what this table would contain is a pointer to a
每个状态都是S、T和U，此表将包含一个指向
vector of moves for that particular state. So, there will be a pointer here and it
该特定状态的运动矢量。所以，这里会有一个指针，它
would point to another. Table, another one dimensional table that would say what we
会指向另一个。表格，另一个一维表格，它会告诉我们
should do zero and what we should do on one. So in the case of S, we wanted to
应该做零，我们应该在一上做什么。所以在S的情况下，我们想要
move to state T if it was a zero and to state U if it was a one. And now when we
如果是0，则移至状态T，如果是1，则移至状态U。现在当我们
go to fill in the entry for T, we see we don't need to duplicate this row. We can
去填写T的条目，我们看到我们不需要复制此行。我们可以的
actually just share this row and similarly for U. And so this table, this
实际上只共享此行，对U也是如此，所以这张表，这张
representation is actually much more compact which just share the rows that are
表示实际上要紧凑得多，只是共享
duplicated in the automaton. And it turns out that in the kinds of automata that we
在自动机中复制。事实证明，在自动机的种类中，我们
look at for lexical analysis it's very, very common to have duplicated rows. And
查看词法分析，有重复行是非常、非常常见的。和
so this can actually resolve the significant compaction of the table
因此，这实际上可以解决表的显著压缩问题
particularly when you consider a number of possible states. Remember there could be.
尤其是当你考虑一些可能的状态时。记住可能会有。
To the N - one states in a DFA. For an NFA with end states. And while the blow up is
到DFA中的N-1个状态。对于具有结束状态的NFA。当爆炸发生的时候
often not the worst case it can be very substantial. So the two dimensional table
通常不是最坏的情况，它可以是非常可观的。所以二维表
we had on the, in the previous slide could actually be quite, quite large and we
在上一张幻灯片中，我们拥有的实际上可能非常非常大，而且我们
keep, we can sometimes have a much more compact representation by little tricks
保持，我们有时可以通过一些小技巧得到更紧凑的表示
like this. Now in this advantage of this particular representation is this extra
像这样。在这个特殊表示的优势中，有一个额外的
interaction, right here. I mean these pointers actually take time to the
互动，就在这里。我的意思是，这些指针实际上需要时间来
reference and so now in our loop will be a little bit slower. We, we, we have to do
引用，所以现在在我们的循环中会稍微慢一点。我们，我们，我们必须要做的是
table look up the reference. Pointer do another tab le look up and then we can
表格查找参考资料。指针再做一次制表符检查，然后我们就可以
make the move. Finally, it's also possible that we might not want to convert to a DFA
行动起来。最后，我们也可能不想转换为DFA
at all. It might be that the particular specification we gave is very expensive to
完全没有。可能是我们给出的特殊规格非常昂贵。
turn into a DFA. The table has just become truly huge and we might be better off just
变成了DFA。桌子刚刚变得很大，我们可能会过得更好
using the NFA directly. And so, one can imagine an implementation of an NFA as
直接使用NFA。因此，可以将NFA的实现想象为
well. We can also implement that via a table. In this case, we would have to have
井。我们也可以通过表格来实现这一点。在这种情况下，我们必须有
a row for each state in the NFA. And we won't do them all here. But we could have
NFA中的每个州都有一行。我们不会在这里把它们都做完。但我们本可以
Rows for every state of the NFA and then, you know where we're going to go if the
NFA的每个州都有行，然后，你知道我们要去哪里，如果
input is zero or if the input is one. And so in this case, And I almost forgot we
输入为零，或者如果输入为1。所以在这种情况下，我差点忘了我们
would also need a transition in the most naive or the most straight forward
也需要一个最天真或最直截了当的过渡
implementation of, where we would go if, if an epsilon. And, and now, remember
执行，我们会去哪里，如果，如果一个ε。还有，现在，记住
because these are NFAs in general, this will be a set of states because we might
因为这些通常是NFA，所以这将是一组状态，因为我们可能
have more than one epsilon transition or more than one transition on zero and one.
在0和1上有多个ε跃迁或多个跃迁。
And so, in this case an epsilon A can go to B. So this would be the set of states B
在这种情况下，εA可以到达B，这将是状态B的集合
and B can go To C or D. And C can only go to E and on one, alright. And D can go to
B可以转到C或D，而C只能转到E和1，好吧。而D可以转到
F on and input of zero and so on. We fill in the rest of the table and this table is
F开并输入零，依此类推。我们填了这张表的睡觉，这张表是
guaranteed to be relatively small because the number of states is limited by the
保证相对较小，因为状态数受
number of states in the NFA and the size of the input alphabet. Once again, we
NFA中的状态数和输入字母表的大小。再一次，我们
could do a sharing of common rows and, and other tricks like that to compress the
可以共享公共行和，以及其他类似的技巧来压缩
table if we like. But now, the inner loop for simulating this automaton is gonna be
如果我们喜欢的话就坐在桌子上。但是现在，模拟这个自动机的内部循环将是
much more expensive because we have to deal with sets of states rather than
要贵得多，因为我们必须处理多个州的事务，而不是
single states. So in every point in time where we can be tracking a set of states
单一州。所以在我们可以跟踪一组状态的每一个时间点
and when we're going to do a move, we have to look up for every state in the set
当我们要采取行动时，我们必须查找集合中的每个州
where it can potentially go including things like the epsilon moves and carry
它可能去的地方，包括ε移动和携带的东西
out all possible epsilon moves so we always have an accurate assessment of the
所有可能的epsilon动作，所以我们总是有一个准确的评估
complete set of states if the NFA could reach. So while this sav es a lot of space
如果NFA可以达到的话，是一套完整的州。因此，虽然这节省了大量空间
in terms of the tables, in terms of the size of the tables it can be much slower
就表而言，就表的大小而言，它可能要慢得多
to execute than deterministic automaton. Summarize, a key idea in the
而不是确定性自动机。总结，这是
implementation of lexical specifications is the conversion of nondeterministic
词汇规范的实现是不确定性的转换
finite automaton to deterministic finite automaton. This is what takes a general
从有限自动机到确定性有限自动机。这就是一位将军所需要的
high level specification use of regular expressions and confer to them to
高级规范使用正则表达式，并将其授予
something as completely deterministic and only uses a few operations per input
完全确定性的东西，每个输入只使用几个操作
character. Now, in practice, tools provide tradeoffs between speed and space. So, so
性格。现在，在实践中，工具提供了速度和空间之间的折衷。所以，所以
DFA's are faster And less compact so the tables can be very large and, and at times
DFA速度更快，而且不那么紧凑，因此表可能非常大，而且有时
that's a practical problem and NFAs are slower to, to implement but more concise.
这是一个实际问题，NFA的实现速度较慢，但更简洁。
And the tools give you generally a series of options often in the form of
这些工具通常会为您提供一系列选项，通常是以下形式
configuration files or command lines which is, that allow you to, to choose whether
配置文件或命令行，即允许您选择是否
you want to be closer to a full DFA, something that's faster and perhaps bigger
您希望更接近于完整的DFA，即更快、可能更大的DFA
or to a pure NFAs, something that's slower but consumes less space.
或者是纯NFA，一种速度更慢但占用空间更少的东西。